Guide to the Allegheny County Health Department's EPA/SIP Air Quality Program Records, 1968-1985 AIS.1997.30
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County Health Department's EPA/SIP Air Quality Program Records
1968-1985
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Allegheny County (Pa.). Health Department
AIS.1997.30
5.75 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
The Allegheny County Health Department EPA/SIP Air Quality Records are part of the records generated by the health department's involvement in creating State Implementation Plans (SIPs) to bring the Pittsburgh area into compliance with federal Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) regulations. The records contain SIP plans, correspondence with the EPA, SIP contracts, and federal grant information from the 1970s and early 1980s.
History
The Allegheny County Health Department is involved in monitoring and controlling air quality in the Pittsburgh area. To assure that the county air quality improves where needed to meet federal air quality standards set by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), the air quality division develops comprehensive State Implementation Plans (SIPs) that are submitted to the state and federal government for approval. The Allegheny County Health Department's Air Pollution Control department was also called the Bureau of Air Pollution Control (BAPC) or the Bureau of Air Quality.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains a portion of the records kept by the Allegheny County Health Department as a function of its participation in federally mandated EPA air quality regulations and related SIP air quality monitoring. Much of the material may have come out of the office of Duputy Director Ron Chleboski. The records are arranged in folders alphabetically by folder title. Subjects include reports on air quality, SIP contracts, correspondence between Allegheny County Health Department and the EPA, and information about federal grants.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Allegheny County Health Department in July 1997.
Previous Citation
Allegheny County Health Department's EPA/SIP Air Quality Program Records, 1968-1985, AIS.1997.30, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Records. Allegheny County Health Department EPA/SIP Air Quality, 1968-1985, Archives of Industrial Society, University Library System, University of Pittsburgh
Air quality management -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Air -- Pollution -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Allegheny County (Pa.); Government; Environment; United States. Environmental Protection Agency; Allegheny County (Pa.). Health Department; Chleboski, Ron
- Appendices for Maintenance Grant, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carnegie-Mellon University SIP Contribution Program, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Chleboski, Ronald J., 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Cleverdon and Hopkins SIP Contract, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Comparison of County and State Air Emission Requirements, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Compliance History for Particulate Matter, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Engineering Science SIP Contract, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- EPA Reports and Correspondence
  - EPA Accounting, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - EPA Audit of Air Pollution Control Grants Given Through 1974, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14-16)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - EPA Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2-5)
  - EPA Maintenance Grant, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - EPA National Air Audit System, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - EPA Semi-Annual Reports, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - EPA Semi-Annual Reports, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - EPA Semi-Annual Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Federal Grant Application
  - Federal Grant Appendices for Maintenance Grant, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Federal Grant Application, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Federal Grant Application, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Federal Grant Applications, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Federal Grant Applications, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Federal Grant Maintenance
  - Federal Grant Maintenance, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Federal Grant Maintenance, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Federal Grant Maintenance, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Federal Grant Maintenance, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Federal Grant Program Status, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Federal Grant, Second Revised Budget, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- State Implementation Plan (SIP), Consultats
  - Intergovernmental Consultation in SIP Revision Process, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Management Subcommittee on SIP Revisions, Minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Materials Consultants Laboratories (MCL) SIP Contract, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Clairton Coke Works and U.S. Steel Corp, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- SIP Revisions, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Ozone and Carbon Monoxide SIP, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- PA Implementation Plan
  - PA Implementation Plan, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - PA Implementation Plan, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - PA Implementation Plan Revisions, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Pennsylvania Department of Environmental Resources (DER) Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- State Implementation Plan (SIP)
  - The Research Corporation of New England (TRC) SIP Contract, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - SIP Contract Correspondence and Negotiations, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - SIP Department of Environmental Resources (DER), 1976-1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - SIP Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)-The Reserach Corporation of New England (TRC)-Bureau of Air Pollution Control (BAPC) Meeting, March 2, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - SIP Management, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - SIP Management, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - SIP Requirements - EPA, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - State Implementation Plan (SIP), 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - State Implementation Plan (SIP), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - State Implementation Plan (SIP), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - SIP Subcommittee, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - SIP Technical, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - SIP Technical, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - SIP Transportation Control Steering Committee, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Strategies for Control of Particulate Matter in Allegheny County, June 1, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sulfur Oxide Implementation Plan, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Sulfur Oxide Implementation Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Technical Subcommittee Minutes, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Title 40, Protection of the Environment, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)